{
    "id": "cf399738f39045c4b557d493b5e588ee",
    "title": "Sequence Of Tenses",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I ………………… rich I would donate a lot of money to charities.",
            "description": "To talk about imaginary situations we use the simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6d7582ce9ad9407b9dda79776935d9ba"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you …………………….. me I would have told you.",
            "description": "To talk about hypothetical situations we use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "asked",
                "have asked",
                "had asked"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "62c4b199b6044991af54de72256627ef"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I have time, I ………………… a movie.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will watch",
                "would watch",
                "would have watched"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "38f4ad69b343447b881d43c6a8776ad8"
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that it …………………… my last chance.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "will be"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "555ca90c0cff4e7ba955b63515e35b9c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Will you wait till I …………………..?",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, it is common to use a simple present in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "return",
                "will return",
                "would return"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a75fb28d61324c1384dcf354d6aa6db9"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can stay here as long as you ……………………….",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, it is common to use a simple present in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "will want",
                "wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b3ed628bd91d4972902e5f78374d1850"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you when they ………………….",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, it is common to use a simple present in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "will arrive",
                "would arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "77232f4cc7a54a798cfcc0e63f202117"
        },
        {
            "question": "She surprised everyone when she …………………….. the first prize.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "wins",
                "won",
                "had won"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6b470c5963464b1787bfe70c938e0d46"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will give 100 dollars to anyone who …………………… my puppy.",
            "description": "Present tenses are used after question words and relative pronouns to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "finds",
                "will find",
                "would find"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0348203786f94cb99ec74659a740a540"
        },
        {
            "question": "We will reach there sooner than you ……………………",
            "description": "In comparisons with as and than both present and future verbs are possible.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "will do",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3e9a2e03d7044d8a9cfdbe5cc336725f"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know how I ……………………………….. there.",
            "description": "When the main clause does not refer to the future, a future tense is required in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "reach",
                "will reach",
                "would reach"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f022441b199047208ad7cd4989217fe4"
        }
    ]
}